{
    "id": "2f8a23b6d6fe4cca9136bda66a5b4cfa",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. the job yesterday itself.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "have finished",
                "had finished"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. all of them to my party.",
            "description": "We often use the present perfect to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "invited",
                "have invited",
                "had invited"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Dad …………………………….. for Singapore yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "See that you .................................... on time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will return",
                "return",
                "returned"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Mother made sure that we ………………………….. good education.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "received",
                "have received",
                "had received"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You would get a promotion if you ……………………………… your target.",
            "description": "In the second conditional we use a simple past tense in the if clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "As I was feeling ill, I ………………………….. a doctor.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "consulted",
                "have consulted",
                "had consulted"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………… for a job since she left university.",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "has been looking",
                "is looking",
                "was looking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. for an hour, you will be able to meet her.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "waited",
                "will wait"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Although I ………………………….. early, I was late for work.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "started",
                "have started"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Father hit the roof when he learned that I ……………………………. my test.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "failed",
                "have failed",
                "had failed"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When I visited him he ........................................ ill for months.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that continued up to a certain point of time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}